7huo **Su**

Postdoc Researcher in Computer Vision and Machine Learning, University of Oulu, Finland

github.com/hellozhuo

I am a computer vision researcher at Center for Machine Vision and Signal Analysis (CMVS) in University of Oulu, Finland. I have defended my thesis in October, 2023. My thesis topic is Efficient Representation Learning for Computer Vision, towards building real-time and compact computer vision models with deep learning. Before that, I visited the AMLab, University of Amsterdam for six months in 2021 and 2022. By April, 2023, I accomplished my 7-month internship at Intel Lab, Germany. As a Postdoc, I am now working on Generative AI and Multimodal learning projects in computer vision.

Interests: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer vision, Math, Coding

PROGRAMMING

◆ Tools/Frameworks

LANGUAGES

Python Matlab C/C++/C++.NET



- > English (fluent)
- > Chinese (native)
- > Finnish (survival)



EXPERIENCE

POSTDOC IN GENERATIVE AI AND MULTIMODAL LEARNING (OULU UNIVERSITY, FINLAND)

NOVEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

I worked on generative models based on stable diffusion and multimodal learning.

Diffusion Models Face Editing Multimodal Learning

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN (INTEL LAB, GERMANY. 7 MONTHS)

SEPTEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

I worked with Matthias Müller at Intel Lab, Germany, on building efficient computer vision networks. The involved tasks are real-time salient object detection and depth estimation.

Computer Vision | Efficient Neural Networks | Real-time Salient Object Detection | Depth Estimation

VISITING RESEARCHER (UNIVERSITY OF AMSTERDAM. 6 MONTHS)

OCTOBER 2021 - MARCH 2022

☑ ELLIS PhD & Postdoc Program ☑ AMLab

I visited AMLab under the ELLIS PhD & Postdoc Program. There, I worked with Prof. Max Welling, on the topic of "Binary SO(3) Equivariant Graph Neural Networks". A paper was published at the International conference on 3D vision 2022.

Graph Neural Networks | Rotation Equivariant | Network Binarization

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (SAMSUNG R&D INSTITUTE CHINA-BEIJING. 3 MONTHS)

MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

I worked in the Machine learning group, on Optical Character Recognition.

Computer Vision Optical Character Recognition

SOFTWARE INTERN (AIHUJING.COM, CHINA. 4 MONTHS)

JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018

I worked as a computer vision intern, on Optical Character Recognition.

Computer Vision Optical Character Recognition



EDUCATION

October 2023

Ph.D, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, University of Oulu, Finland

October 2018

Thesis: LBP Inspired Efficient Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Representation Learning

Supervisor: Dr. Li Liu; Opponent: Prof. Karen Eguiazarian; Custos: Prof. Matti Pietikäinen Computer Vision Network compression Binary neural networks Efficient Graph neural networks

March 2018

M.Sc, AUTOMATION SCIENCE AND ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, Beihang University, China

September 2015

Thesis: Salient Object Detection for Single Images

Supervisors: Prof. Hong Zheng, Prof. Baochang Zhang

GPA: 3.24/4.0

Image processing | Salient object detection | Machine learning

June 2015 September 2011

B.Sc, AUTOMATION SCIENCE AND ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, Beihang University, China

Topic: Pattern Recognition

GPA: 3.68/4.0

Pattern recognition | Machine learning

🗐 Papers (first author)

- 1. Zhuo Su et al. "Boosting Convolutional Neural Networks with Middle Spectrum Grouped Convolution", IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (TNNLS), 2024
 - d pdf ogithub.com/hellozhuo/msgc
- 2. Zhuo Su et al. "Lightweight Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Visual Representation Learning", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2023
- 3. Zhuo Su et al. "Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Edge Detection", IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (oral presentation)
 - d pdf github.com/hellozhuo/pidinet
- 4. Zhuo Su et al. "Dynamic Group Convolution for Accelerating Convolutional Neural Networks", European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020 (spotlight presentation)
 - pdf github.com/hellozhuo/dgc
- 5. Zhuo Su et al. "BIRD: Learning Binary and Illumination Robust Descriptor for Face Recognition", British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2019
 - 🗹 pdf 🕠 github.com/hellozhuo/bird-descriptor
- 6. Zhuo Su et al. "SVNet: Where SO(3) Equivariance Meets Binarization on Point Cloud Representation", IEEE International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2022
 - pdf pdf github.com/hellozhuo/svnet
- 7. Zhuo Su et al. "From Local Binary Patterns to Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Visual Representation Learning", Scandinavian Conference on Image Analysis (SCIA), 2023 **☑** pdf
- 8. Zhuo Su et al. "Spatial and Temporal Difference Network for Real-time Salient Object Detection" (in submission to TPAMI, 2023)

Papers (co-author)

- 1. Chao Xiao et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Highly Efficient and Unsupervised Framework for Moving Object Detection in Satellite Videos", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2024
- 2. Huali Xu et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Enhancing Information Maximization with Distance-Aware Contrastive Learning for Source-Free Cross-Domain Few-Shot Learning", IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2024
- 3. Zitong Yu et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Searching central difference convolutional networks for face anti-spoofing", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020
- 4. Wanxia Deng, Zhuo Su et al. "Deep ladder reconstruction classification network for unsupervised domain adaptation", Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL), 2021
- 5. Jiehua Zhang, Zhuo Su, Li Liu, "Median Pixel Difference Convolutional Network for Robust Face Recognition", British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2021
- 6. Jiehua Zhang, Zhuo Su et al. "Dynamic Binary Neural Network by learning channel-wise thresholds", The International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, & Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2021

Scientific Contributions

TEACHING ASSISTANT, UNIVERSITY OF OULU (Prof. LI LIU)

2018 - 2022

I have been working as the teaching assistant of the course "Deep Learning" in University of Oulu in the past years.

Deep Learning Network Compression Pytorch

INVITED REVIEWER 2019 - PRESENT

Journals

TPAMI, TIP, TMM, TCSVT, Neurocomputing, PRL, CVIU, TOMM

CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, ICME, ICASSP, ACMMM, AAAI, ACCV, ICPR, PRCV